<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>books on Peter Klipfel</title>
    <link>/tags/books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in books on Peter Klipfel</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 21:42:47 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My 2023 Book List</title>
      <link>/blog/2023_books/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 21:42:47 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2023_books/</guid>
      <description>Here is a list of all the books I read in 2023, and a short summary of what I thought.
 The Comfort Crisis - Michael Easter  7/10 I read this as a precursor to some surgery that I was concerned about. It isn&amp;rsquo;t specifically about surgery, but it helped put me in the right mindset to prepare for discomfort and pain from the surgery.   How the World Really Works - Vaclav Smil  5/10 Kind of interesting, but the author felt self-important and pushy for much of the book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My 2022 Book List</title>
      <link>/blog/2022_books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 21:42:47 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2022_books/</guid>
      <description>Here is a list of all the books I read in 2022, and a short summary of what I thought.
 Klara and the Sun - Kazuo Ishiguro  6/10 This book was fine. It articulates an interesting vision for where AI and robotics could lead us, but isn&amp;rsquo;t particularly creative or thought provoking in its predictions. As a story of growth and learning, it is also&amp;hellip; fine. Worth a read, but not the top of the pile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My 2021 Book List</title>
      <link>/blog/2021_books/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 21:42:47 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021_books/</guid>
      <description>Here is a list of all the books I read in 2021, and a short summary of what I thought.
 The Intelligint Investor - Benjamin Graham  9 / 10 This was a great read. Not a ton of new advice, over other investment books I have read, but it reinvigorated my enthusiasm for lazy investing.   Beginner&amp;rsquo;s Mind - Yo-Yo Ma  7 / 10 This was a pretty light ruad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The complete works of H.P. Lovecraft</title>
      <link>/blog/book_review_complete_works_of_lovecraft/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 20:50:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/book_review_complete_works_of_lovecraft/</guid>
      <description>Recommendation Do not waste your time. There is so much other, better reading out there.
If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in the works and their historical significance, I&amp;rsquo;d recommend just reading summaries. There are a few interesting ideas in his works, but if you have read sci-fi, you are probably already familiar with them.
My thoughts I picked this up as an audiobook without knowing what I was getting myself into. The first red flag that I got was that the narrator explaining that I should look past the racism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My 2020 Book list</title>
      <link>/blog/2020_books/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 21:42:47 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020_books/</guid>
      <description>Here is a list of all the books I read in 2020, and a short summary of what I thought. Toward the end of the year, I started writing some longer summaries of the books including what I thought of them.
 AI Superpowers - Kai-Fu Lee  6 / 10 This is a good read. It is obviously biased toward China being the greatest place for businesses, but has interesting things to say.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing Your Life</title>
      <link>/blog/book_review_designing_your_life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 16:55:33 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/book_review_designing_your_life/</guid>
      <description>Recommendation Overall, I would recommend this book to anyone who isn&amp;rsquo;t sure what they should be doing with their life. I like the techniques proposed in this book, but it feels like the authors are trying to sell me on something throughout the book, which was a bit off-putting.
My Thoughts I recently spoke to a remote class of college students, and they were very concerned with how to find a job and how to live their best lives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Time Paradox</title>
      <link>/blog/book_review_the_time_paradox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 16:57:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/book_review_the_time_paradox/</guid>
      <description>Recommendation I would recommend this book, but I think you might be able to get a similar amount of information by reading their blog posts. This book has a very useful mental model, and it has helped me identify and artculate things that I like and dislike about myself and other people.
My thoughts Paradox 1  Time is one of the most powerful influences on our thoughts, feelings, and actions, yet we are usually totally unaware of the effect of time in our lives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hell Yeah or No by Derek Sivers</title>
      <link>/blog/book_review_hell_yeah_or_no/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 16:57:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/book_review_hell_yeah_or_no/</guid>
      <description>Recommendation This was a good book. It&amp;rsquo;s a quick read, and I found it very enjoyable. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how much of that was because I think it will be a useful book for others to read or if it was simply nice to read about someone that I seem to have so much in common with.
My thoughts Similarly to Your Music and People, I was surprised to discover how short this book was, but it is concise and so enjoyable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Music and People by Derek Sivers</title>
      <link>/blog/book_review_your_music_and_people/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 16:57:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/book_review_your_music_and_people/</guid>
      <description>Recommendation This book comes with my highest recommendation. It&amp;rsquo;s short, and every page packs a punch. Reading it will be a good use of your time.
My thoughts Upon purchasing this book, I was a bit disappointed that it was so short. I felt a bit duped for spending $15 on the digital copy of a short book. I&amp;rsquo;m a big fan of Derek Sivers, and I&amp;rsquo;d picked up that he&amp;rsquo;s kind of minimalist and concise, so I hoped that I&amp;rsquo;d get the value out of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breath by James Nestor</title>
      <link>/blog/book_review_breath/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 16:57:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/book_review_breath/</guid>
      <description>Recommendation This was a good book. I&amp;rsquo;ve struggled to keep up a practice of meditation, but I find that breathwork is a good way to keep my meditation practice up. With breathwork I can strive for things like longer breath hold times, lower resting heart rate, and imrpoved cardio performance.
I listened to this book as an audio book, and the appendix had some narrated breathing exercises. For this reason, I would recommend listening to the audiobook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My philosophy of book reviews</title>
      <link>/blog/book_reviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 16:57:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/book_reviews/</guid>
      <description>Book reviews I read and listen to a lot of books. Historically, I&amp;rsquo;ve just created a sentence or two after finishing the book or lecture series, but after reading the Mahabharata, I wanted a better format for discussing the books that I had been reading. Coincidentally, this was right around the time that I discovered Derek Sivers&#39; book reviews; my book reviews are partially inspired by his posts, but follow a different format.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
